(
"ai_sub_version": "1.11.0",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 3,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
#尾丸ポルカ生誕祭2026
新曲のお披露目あり！
Glitter of Love
#OmaruPolkaBirthday2026
New song reveal!
Glitter of Love
ポルカのライブ過去最多
ホロメンゲスト10名
Polka's live with her most guests ever:
10 Hololive members
1, 2, 3, 4
遥か空響いてる
Echoing in the distant sky,
祈りは奇跡に
Prayers become miracles...
ETERNAL BLAZE
作詞：水樹奈々
作曲：上松範康(Elements Garden)
ETERNAL BLAZE
Lyrics: Nana Mizuki
Composition: Noriyasu Agematsu (Elements Garden)
真昼の月追い越して
Overtaking the midday moon,
流れてく涙の粒
The falling teardrops...
迷いなく包み込む温もりに出会った
Encountered a warmth that envelops without hesitation
真っ白な雪のように どこまでも素直な言葉
Words as honest as pure white snow,
鉄の羽纏った 僕を動かしていく
Clad in iron wings, they set me in motion
傷つく度 優しくなれる
Every time I get hurt, I can become kinder
君のその笑顔だけ
If only for your smile,
守り抜きたい 願いはひとつ
There's one wish I want to protect till the end
時を越え刻まれた 悲しみの記憶
The memories of sadness carved across time
まっすぐに受け止める 君は光の戦士
Accepting them head-on, you are a warrior of light
あの日胸に灯った 永遠の炎
The eternal flame lit in my heart that day
深い闇解き放って 自由の扉開いてく
Unleashing the deep darkness, opening the door to freedom
強く果てない未来へ
Toward a strong and endless future
深い緑の月に 映し出す心の影
The shadow of my heart reflected on the deep green moon
寂しげに呟いた 君の傍にいたい
Whispered loneliness, I want to be by your side
真実と向き合うこと 教えてくれた勇気は
The courage you gave me to face the truth
僕を駆け巡って 夢に目覚めてゆく
Courses through me, awakening into a dream
触れ合う気持ち 離れないように
So our shared feelings don't drift apart
しっかりと抱きしめて
I'll hold you tight,
確かな想い貫いてゆく
Pushing through with certain feelings
銀の海に隠した 空白のページ
The blank pages hidden in the silver sea
君だけが知っている 本当の僕を見せて
Show me the real me that only you know
吹き荒れる切なさに 生まれゆく誓い
The oath born from the raging sadness
もう何も怖くないよ
I'm not afraid of anything anymore
結んだ視線そらさずに
Without looking away from our joined gaze
大切な今 始める
Starting the precious "now"
君が君でいられる場所 幻にさせないように
The place where you can be yourself, I won't let it become an illusion
消えない雨の苦しみも
Even the pain of the never-ending rain,
鍵を壊してぶつけてよ
Break the lock and release it to me
隣にいるから 全てを信じて
Because I'm right here by your side, believe in everything
時を越え刻まれた 悲しみの記憶
The memories of sadness carved across time
まっすぐに受け止める 君は光の戦士
Accepting them head-on, you are a warrior of light
あの日胸に灯った 永遠の炎
The eternal flame lit in my heart that day
深い闇解き放って
Unleashing the deep darkness...
…解き放って
...unleash
自由の扉　開いてく
I'll open the door to freedom
強く果てない未来へ
To a strong and endless future
そしてここから始まる
And it begins from here
お待たせ、みんな！
Sorry to keep you waiting, everyone!
今年もポルカの誕生日が始まったー！
Polka's birthday has begun again this year!
タイトルは、かっこいい「Glitter of Love」！
The title is the cool "Glitter of Love"!
というわけで、ハッシュタグはこちら！
So, here's the hashtag!
「#尾丸ポルカ生誕祭2026」で
Using "#OmaruPolkaBirthday2026"
いっぱい、いっぱい呟いてね！
please tweet a lot and a lot!
はい！いや〜、今回のテーマがまず…
Yes! Wow, the theme this time is...
「愛と勇気と戦う女の子」になってます！
"Girls who fight with love and courage"!
そして！見てください、このステージ！
And! Look at this stage!
えい！はぁ〜、すごい広い！
Hup! Whoa, it's so huge!
おお、なんとですね、広いんですけど、
まずスクリーンが超巨大！
Oh, and though it's huge,
first off, the screen is massive!
大迫力！
So powerful!
なんとなんといつもの３倍くらい頑張りました！
Believe it or not, we worked about three times harder than usual!
いや、頑張ってもらいました！
Or rather, I had them work hard!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
というわけでですね、ここから
ゲストの方々がたくさんいらっしゃいます！
So, there are many guests coming from here on out!
もうホロメンだけなら多分、
尾丸ポルカ史上最多のゲスト数だと思っております！
I think this will be the largest number of Hololive members
ever in Polka history!
それをね、これからノンストップでお送りするので、
楽しんでいってください！
We'll be presenting them non-stop from now,
so please enjoy!
というわけで、いくぞー！
So, let's go!
遺伝子レベルの
At the genetic level
INDEPENDENT!
絶望も希望も抱いて
Embracing both despair and hope
あがけ命尽きるまで
Struggle until life runs out
星天ギャラクシィクロス
Seiten Galaxy Cross
光としぶきのキッス
A kiss of light and spray
恋のような
Like love
虹のバースデー
A rainbow birthday
どんな美しき日も
No matter how beautiful the day
何か生まれ
Something is born
何かが死ぬ
Something dies
せめて歌おう
At least let's sing
I LOVE YOU
世界が非情地獄だとしても
Even if the world is a heartless hell
せめて伝えよう
At least let's convey it
I LOVE YOU
解放の時は来た
The time for liberation has come
星降る天へと響き飛べ
Resonate and fly to the star-filled heavens
Everybody song!
Stardust!
そして奇跡は待つものじゃなくて
And miracles aren't something to wait for
その手で作るものと吠えろ
Howl that they are something you make with your own hands
涙した過去を苦味を
The tearful past, the bitterness
レクイエムにして
Turn them into a requiem
星空全部の力で
With all the power of the starry sky
輝けフューチャー
Shine, future
信じて刺せ
Believe and pierce through
星天ギャラクシィクロス
Seiten Galaxy Cross
一人じゃないことを
That you are not alone
やがて君は知る日のため
Soon, for the day you realize it
指先伝うアストロ
Astro flowing through fingertips
分かち合って
Sharing it
明日に向かう
Facing tomorrow
永遠なる空に
In the eternal sky
I FEEL YOU
自由な魂は殺せはしない
You cannot kill a free soul
不滅なる夢に
In the immortal dream
I FEEL YOU
大志へと剣を握れ
Grasp the sword towards great ambition
運命も終局も断ち切る力で
With the power to cut through both fate and the end
そして重なった勇気
And the overlapping courage
突き抜け煌めき
A piercing brilliance
十字となって闇を暴く
Becoming a cross to expose the darkness
駆け抜けたその先には
Beyond where we've run through
神様も知らない
Not even God knows
歴史が今 光り誇る
The history now shines with pride
My vibrant brave heart!
この絆は
This bond is
星天ギャラクシィクロス
Seiten Galaxy Cross
逆光の翼で
With wings of backlighting
Just believe!
焦がれるほど想って
Thinking of it so much it burns
Pre-mission!
過去を背負い戦おう
Let's fight, carrying the past
そして奇跡は待つものじゃなくて
And miracles aren't something to wait for
その手で創るものだと吠えろ
Roar that it's something you create with your own hands
何度だって 何度だって立ち上がろうか
Let's rise up again and again
星天全能の力で
With the power of absolute galactic might
輝け futureは
Shine, our future
信じて照らせ
Believe and light the way
星天ギャラクシィクロス
Seiten Galaxy Cross
Let's sing! Let's spin! Let's dance! Let's go!
Let's smile! Let's fly! プリキュア！
Let's smile! Let's fly! Precure!
Let's sing! Let's spin! Let's dance! Let's go!
Let's smile! Let's fly!
ときめきで上書き 世界 未来
Overwriting the world and future with excitement
1+1+1は無限
1+1+1 is infinity
唇からこぼれる歌は La-La-La プリズム La-La-La
The song spilling from the lips is La-La-La Prism La-La-La
リズム眩しい光反射
Rhythm, dazzling light reflection
3人寄れば最高最強
When the three of us get together, we're the best and strongest
始まるよ 第一希望 Like! Enjoy! Together!
It's starting, our first wish, Like! Enjoy! Together!
ときめき止まらない
Excitement won't stop
ハミング！
Humming!
約束！
Promise!
感情！
Emotions!
合点レスポンス！
Agreed response!
輝き プリディクション
Shining prediction
好きなフレーズを
Our favorite phrases
深呼吸して 夢の背中で
Take a deep breath on the back of dreams
君 あなたのもとへ For you もっともっと
To you, to your side, For you, more and more
輝き合えるね みんな プリキュア！
We can shine together, everyone, Precure!
Let's go!
人見知りに いつだって
Even when feeling shy, we'll always
笑顔移しあおう
Share smiles with each other
君がいるからパワー生まれるよ 今日も
Because you're here, power is born, today too
Let's sing! Let's spin! Let's dance! Let's go!
Let's smile! Let's fly! プリキュア！
Let's smile! Let's fly! Precure!
Let's sing! Let's spin! Let's dance! Let's go!
Let's smile! Let's fly!
一緒だから感じた ハッピー Only one
The happiness I felt because we're together, Only one
1×1×1は無敵
1x1x1 is invincible
出し惜しみはなしで全部あげたい プリズム La-La-La プリズム La-La-La
No holding back, I want to give it all, Prism La-La-La Prism La-La-La
ハプニングさえも絶好 Wonderful
Even mishaps are perfect, Wonderful
3人寄れば 文殊の知恵
Three people together have the wisdom of Monju
見せるよきっと 伝説のライブ アンコール頂戴
I'll surely show you a legendary live, please give us an encore
ゆるいビート！
Loose beat!
ポップホープ！
Pop hope!
賛成！
Agreed!
オールウェルカム！
All welcome!
カテゴライズいらないね
We don't need categories, do we?
好きな思い切り
With all our favorite things
羽根広げて ハートの奥の奥へ
Spread your wings, into the deep, deep of your heart
Have you? 命は
Have you? Life is
輝きでできていいの？
Is it okay if it's made of brilliance?
ギャップ！
Gap!
ビッグスクリーンも はみ出しちゃう
Even the big screen is overflowing
嬉しい 楽しい マーベラス
Happy, fun, marvelous
君を知って 知らない自分に会えたよ 今日も
Knowing you, I met a self I didn't know, today too
Let's sing! Let's spin! Let's dance! Let's go!
Let's smile! Let's fly! プリキュア！
Let's smile! Let's fly! Precure!
Let's sing! Let's spin! Let's dance! Let's go!
Let's smile! Let's fly!
やっほー！
Yay!
瞳吸い込まれに
I want to be drawn into your eyes
いつまでも笑顔映し合おう
Let's reflect our smiles forever
君がいるからパワー
Because you're here, power...
生まれるよ今日も
...is born today too
Try Try Trio Let's Sing! Let's Swing! Let's Dance! Let's Bound! Let's Smile! Let's Fly!
ウープリーズショー！
Woo, please show!
Let's Sing! Let's Swing! Let's Dance! Let's Bound! Let's Smile! Let's Fly!
ウーーーーハイッ！
Woo... High!
暗闇の真ん中
In the middle of the darkness
まっすぐな眼差し
With a steady gaze
立ち上がる姿
The way you stand up
ちゃんと見ていたよ
I was watching you properly
閉じ込められそうな
As if I'm about to be trapped
心を奮い立たせ
Stirring up my heart
収まりきらない
It won't be contained
輝きを放ち
Releasing a radiance
射抜かれた胸の奥
Deep within my pierced chest
泣き伏した眩しさは
The radiance I cried over
それだけでも自由になれる 待っていて
Just that alone makes me free, wait for me
取り戻したい
I want to take back
光の世界
The world of light
その笑顔
That smile,
勇気
courage,
涙
tears,
夢 希望の兆し
signs of dreams and hope
響き合う明日を
For a resonating tomorrow,
願う内側から
from deep within my prayers,
生まれる
it's born,
私たちのハーモニー
our harmony
響け
Resonate!
それでも暗闇は
Even so, the darkness
訪れてしまうもの
is something that will come
惑わされない
I won't be misled,
君は君だから
because you are you
私会えた日々が
The days we were able to meet
ハートを輝かせる
make my heart shine
一人じゃないこと
That I'm not alone,
気付かせてくれる
you make me realize
抱えきれないほどの
So much that I can't carry it all,
ありがとうの代わりに
instead of saying thank you,
鍵をかけて
I'll lock it
一つになる 受け止めて
to become one, please accept it
取り戻すんだ
I will take it back,
光の未来
the future of light
今熱い
Right now, hot
想いつなげ 叶えに行くよ
connecting our feelings, I'm going to make it come true
君と一緒に
Together with you,
願える奇跡
the miracle we can wish for,
重ねて
overlap them,
広がっていくハーモニー
and our harmony will spread
響け
Resonate!
目覚めるときがきたね
The time to wake up has come, hasn't it?
本当の自分になる
I'll become my true self
満ちる 運命
A fulfilling destiny
取り戻したい
I want to take back
光の世界
The world of light
その笑顔
That smile,
勇気
courage,
涙
tears,
夢 希望の兆し
signs of dreams and hope
君と明日を
With you, for tomorrow,
願う内側から
from deep within my prayers,
生まれる
it's born,
私たちのハーモニー
our harmony
響け
Resonate!
Day by day 日に日に募るの 乙女心
Day by day, day after day, my maidenly heart grows
同じ...
Same...
1×1 プラスなら 目まいの大人しい人
1 times 1 plus... a dizzy, quiet person.
さあカッコよくはない だけど優しい
Now, he's not cool, but he's kind.
いつも頼れる彼
He's someone I can always rely on.
おたく恋愛相談の帰り道
On the way back from an otaku love consultation.
なんだって話せる親友の女の子
A girl who's a best friend I can talk to about anything.
スポーツ万能で
Great at sports,
勉強もできて
and smart, too,
女子力MAXで
with maximum feminine charm.
どこにでもある
Something common,
よくあること
that happens everywhere.
急に彼女が
Suddenly, she said...
「あのね、実は私、好きな人がいるの」って
"You know, actually, there's someone I like."
ちょ、マジで!?
Wait, seriously!?
三角形 三角形
Triangle, triangle,
の恋は気まぐれ
this love is fickle.
一瞬で 一瞬で
In an instant, in an instant,
崩れるバランス
the balance crumbles.
ベタなマンガみたいなフラグ
A cliché manga-like flag.
まさか自分が立てちゃうなんて残念すぎます
It's too unfortunate that I'm the one who set it up.
三角形 三角形
Triangle, triangle,
の恋は不安定
this love is unstable.
なんちゃって なんちゃって
Just kidding, just kidding,
じゃ済まないカテゴリー
not a category that ends with that.
恋と友情 ゆらゆら揺れて
Love and friendship, swaying back and forth.
なんか青春しちゃってます
I'm feeling like I'm in my youth.
私 困っちゃってます
I'm in a bind.
乾杯でお似合いすぎるわさてこんな日
A toast! We look so good together on a day like this.
悔しいけど どうかそんなんじゃなくて本心
It's frustrating, but please, I'm being serious.
っていうか既に応援モード
Or rather, I'm already in support mode.
むしろ清々しい
Actually, it's refreshing.
だけど彼女は不思議な顔
But she has a strange look on her face.
真剣なんだって
She says she's serious.
「そうじゃなくて私、あなたがすき。ごめん」って
"No, I like you. Sorry."
ちょ、マジで!?
Wait, seriously!?
三角形 三角形
Triangle, triangle,
の恋は気まぐれ
this love is fickle.
一瞬で 一瞬で
In an instant, in an instant,
崩れるバランス
the balance crumbles.
私 あなた 彼女と私
Me, you, her and me.
超絶複雑百合展開は想定外です
This incredibly complex yuri development is unexpected.
三角形 三角形
Triangle, triangle,
の恋は不安定
this love is unstable.
なんちゃって なんちゃって
Just kidding, just kidding,
じゃ済まないカテゴリー
not a category that ends with that.
解けないパズル 与えたもうた神よ
God, you've given me an unsolvable puzzle.
うなっちゃいます
I'm groaning.
私 悩んじゃいます
I'm worrying.
ああもう! すごいヤバイ!
Ah, geez! This is crazy!
ひどいよー
That's mean!
待って! でもそういう意味じゃなくて!
Wait! But I didn't mean it that way!
だって女の子同士だし!
But we're both girls!
ねえ神様、どうしたらいいの?
Hey God, what should I do?
私、どうしたいの?
What do I want to do?
HELP ME!
なんか変だ 愛に国境も年も性別も関係ない
Something's weird. Love knows no borders, age, or gender.
けどけどけど
But, but, but...
三角形 三角形
Triangle, triangle,
の恋は気まぐれ
this love is fickle.
一瞬で 一瞬で
In an instant, in an instant,
崩れるバランス
the balance crumbles.
普通の恋 夢見てたのに
I was dreaming of a normal love.
ノーマル捨てての私じゃちょっと無理ゲーすぎます
It's too much of an impossible game for me after throwing away "normal".
三角形 三角形
Triangle, triangle,
の恋は不安定
this love is unstable.
なんちゃって なんちゃって
Just kidding, just kidding,
じゃ済まないカテゴリー
not a category that ends with that.
彼女のこと好きになれたらなんて妄想しちゃいます
I find myself fantasizing about what if I could fall in love with her.
私 どかしちゃってます
I'm losing my mind.
PHOENIX PRAYER
作詞・作曲：中村未来
Lyrics & Composition: Miku Nakamura
轟々と続くショート・ショート
Short stories that continue roaringly
喪失は絶対で 糸解けば
Loss is absolute, and if you unravel the threads
今夜 輪廻消火 悲しみが
Tonight, reincarnation is extinguished, sadness...
混沌の子守唄 歌ってるよ
...is singing a lullaby of chaos.
運命に理由があるのならば
If there is a reason for fate
すべてを賭けてみたいの
I want to try betting everything
あなたを守りたい
I want to protect you
どこまでも高く飛べるわ
We can fly as high as we want
どこまでも強く強くなれるわ
We can become as strong as we want
信じて 私に出会えた奇跡
Believe in the miracle of meeting me
霧開く不死鳥の炎灯いて
Lighting the phoenix's flame that clears the fog
あなたの側
By your side
ブラブラ 眼差し泣きたくなるの
Dangling, your gaze makes me want to cry
フラッシュバック フラッシュバック
Flashback, flashback
振りほどけ 焦勢 挑み続けろ
Shake it off, keep challenging the impatience
飄々と佇むホット・ショット
A hotshot standing aloofly
私が必用でしょ？
You need me, don't you?
今夜 輪廻勝者 正しさが
Tonight, the winner of reincarnation, correctness...
ストレート 最前線に押し出すよ
...is pushed straight to the front lines
運命に理由があるのならば
If there is a reason for fate
優しい世界をあげたい
I want to give you a kind world
あなたを包むわ
I will embrace you
どこまでも早く射抜くわ
We will pierce through as fast as we can
どこまでも熱く熱く焦がすわ
We will burn as hotly as we can
信じて 私に出会えた奇跡
Believe in the miracle of meeting me
霧開く不死鳥の炎灯いて
Lighting the phoenix's flame that clears the fog
あなたの側
By your side
ブラブラ 仇越し光を見せて
Dangling, show me the light through the grudge
フラッシュバック フラッシュバック
Flashback, flashback
許さない 憂勢 進み続けろ
I won't forgive the melancholy, keep moving forward
尽きるまで 側に居ると
Until I'm exhausted, I'll be by your side
鼓動が早くて 眩暈がする
My heart is beating fast, I feel dizzy
すべて捧げる
I offer everything
もう決めたの
I've already decided
最後のチャンスだから
Because it's the last chance
もう離さない
I won't let go anymore
あなたに問う 未来の風
I ask you, the wind of the future
跨って行け
Ride on it and go!
どこまでも高く飛べるわ
We can fly as high as we want
どこまでも強く強くなれるわ
We can become as strong as we want
信じて 私に出会えた奇跡
Believe in the miracle of meeting me
闇夜も望めば 輝夜にするから
Even a dark night, if you wish, I'll turn it into a bright night
霧開く不死鳥の炎灯いて
Lighting the phoenix's flame that clears the fog
あなたの側
By your side
ブラブラ 眼差し泣きたくなるの
Dangling, your gaze makes me want to cry
フラッシュバック フラッシュバック
Flashback, flashback
振りほどけ 焦勢 挑み続けろ
Shake it off, keep challenging the impatience
ブラブラ 仇越し光を見せて
Dangling, show me the light through the grudge
フラッシュバック フラッシュバック
Flashback, flashback
許さない 憂勢 進み続けろ
I won't forgive the melancholy, keep moving forward
ダイアモンド クレバス
Diamond Crevasse
神様に恋をしていた頃は
Back when I was in love with God
こんな別れが来るとは思ってなかったよ
I never thought a parting like this would come
もう二度と触れられないなら
If I can never touch you again
せめて最後に　もう一度抱きしめて欲しかったよ
At least one last time, I wanted you to hold me
It's long long goodbye
It's a long, long goodbye
さよなら　さよなら
Goodbye, goodbye
何度だって自分に無情に言い聞かせて
Telling myself over and over, heartlessly
手を振るのは優しさだよね
Waving my hand is a form of kindness, right?
今　強さが欲しい
Now, I want strength
あなたに出会い　輝いて　あたしが生まれて
Meeting you, shining, I was born
愛すればこそ　愛あればこそ
Precisely because I love you, because there is love
希望のない奇跡を待って　どうなるの
What happens if I wait for a miracle without hope?
涙ににじむ星の瞬きは　Gold
The twinkling of the stars, blurred by tears, is Gold
忘れないよ　あなたの温もりも
I won't forget your warmth
その優しさも　すべて包んでくれた両手も
Nor that kindness, nor your hands that wrapped around everything
It's long long goodbye
It's a long, long goodbye
さよなら　さよなら　愛しい人
Goodbye, goodbye, my beloved
あなたがいたから　歩いてこれた
Because you were there, I could walk this far
ひとりなんかじゃなかったよね
I wasn't alone, was I?
今　答えが欲しい
Now, I want an answer
燃えるような流星　捕まえて　火を灯して
Catch a burning meteor and light a fire
愛していたい　愛されてたい
I want to keep loving, I want to be loved
冷えた身体ひとつで　世界はどうなるの
With just this chilled body, what will become of the world?
張り続けてた虚勢が　溶けてく
The bluff I kept putting up is melting away
Long goodbye...
どうしてだろう　涙あふれて
I wonder why tears are overflowing
止められない
I can't stop them
あなたに出会い　輝いて　あたしが生まれて
Meeting you, shining, I was born
愛すればこそ　愛あればこそ
Precisely because I love you, because there is love
希望のない奇跡を待って　どうなるの
What happens if I wait for a miracle without hope?
涙ににじむ星の瞬きは...
The twinkling of the stars, blurred by tears...
もし生まれ変わって　また巡り会えるのなら
If I am reborn and we can meet again
その時もきっと　あたしを見つけ出して
In that moment too, please find me
もう二度と離さないで　捕まえてて
Never let me go again, hold on to me
一人じゃないと
Whisper to me that...
ささやいてほしい
...I'm not alone,
プラネット
Planet.
Paradise Lost
作詞：畑 亜貴　作曲：菊田 大介
Lyrics: Aki Hata / Composition: Daisuke Kikuta
聖なる瞳が
When those holy eyes
痛みを映したら
reflect pain,
振り向いてごらん
turn around and see,
情熱放つトリック
a trick that releases passion.
崩れる足元
With the ground crumbling,
二人は戻れない
the two of us can't go back.
差し伸べた手をほどかないで
Don't let go of the hand you've reached out.
消えるよまた
They'll vanish again,
優しい日々が
those gentle days.
思い出を穢すのは
I can't forgive anyone for
許せない
defiling my memories.
ここは裏切りの庭
This is the Garden of Betrayal,
彷徨う心の果てに
at the end of a wandering heart.
光を求めて
Seeking the light,
祈る言葉届けあなたに
I send words of prayer to you.
囚われの羽が
Imprisoned wings
遥かな空へと向かう
head toward the distant sky.
信じたいよ私たち
I want to believe that we
孤独じゃない
are not alone.
分かり合う
Understanding each other
(響き合う)
(Resonating)
絆の中
within our bonds.
離さない
I won't let go
(離れない)
(I won't leave),
始まるディスティニー
the destiny begins.
新たな願いに
When the chains are undone
鎖解ける時
by a new wish,
休ませてくれる
it lets me rest
深い眠りに
in a deep sleep.
僅かな希望が
A faint hope
私を強くする
makes me stronger,
ぬくもりに触れてみたいから
because I want to feel your warmth.
蘇れば
If it revives,
儚き命
this fleeting life,
繰り返す愛おしさが
the repeating affection
導いた
has guided us.
胸に泡沫の調べ
A transient melody in my heart,
流れる世界の終わりに
at the end of a flowing world,
諦めはしない
I won't give up,
今がつなぐ明日探そう
let's find the tomorrow that the present connects to.
千切れ舞う羽は
The torn and dancing wings
未来の空にも向かう
also head toward the sky of the future.
忘れないで私たち
Don't forget that we
ひとつのクリスタル
are one single crystal.
輝いて
Shine
(感じて)
(Feel it),
終われないのよ
it's not over yet.
離さない
I won't let go
(離れない)
(I won't leave),
誓いのディスティニー
the destiny of our oath.
離さない
I won't let go
見つめて Paradise Lost
Gaze into Paradise Lost
Wow wow...
やっとみんな会えたね！
Finally, we could all meet!
GIRLS' LEGEND U
Don't stop, non-stop the finish!
たったったっ 全力 走りたい
Tattatta, I want to run at full speed
芝と 砂と 君の 追い切りメニュー
Turf, dirt, and your final training menu
タナ タナ 声出せ 叫べ
Tana tana, raise your voice and shout
Oh oh...
とりゃあ！ ハイ！ オイ！ ハイ！ オイ！
Toryah! Hai! Oi! Hai! Oi!
たったったっ 全力 上がりたい
Tattatta, I want to rise at full speed
譲れない 夢の 途中
In the middle of a dream I can't give up
Wow wow... 始めよう ここから最高のストーリー
Wow wow... Let's start the best story from here
Oh oh oh oh...
あぁ 憧れの地へ
Ah, toward the land of yearning
語り合ったメモリー
The memories we shared together
もうドキドキもトキメキも 抑えられないたまんない
I can't contain the pounding heart and excitement anymore
熱いハラハラが止まらない！
The hot suspense won't stop!
君と 走り競いゴール目指し
With you, running and competing toward the goal
遥か響け届けミュージック
Resonate and reach far, music
ずっとずっとずっとずっと想い 夢がきっと叶うなら
If the feelings and dreams I've always held surely come true
あの日君に感じた 何かを信じて
Believing in something I felt from you that day
春も夏も秋も冬も声 描き焦がれ走れ
Spring, summer, autumn, and winter voices, run toward the yearning we drew
あぁ 勝利へ！
Ah, toward victory!
Don't stop, non-stop the finish!
たったったっ 全力 弾けたい
Tattatta, I want to burst at full speed
大出会い 決意 絆になった
A great encounter, a determination that became a bond
ハンザ ハンザ 本気で 叫べ
Hands up, hands up, shout with all your heart
Oh oh...
とりゃあ！ ハイ！ オイ！ ハイ！ オイ！
Toryah! Hai! Oi! Hai! Oi!
たったったっ 全力 笑いたい
Tattatta, I want to laugh at full speed
カフス ロゴ 真ん中
Cuffs, logo, right in the center
Wow wow... リアルに ここから上昇ストーリー
Wow wow... A rising story from here in reality
Oh oh oh oh...
駆け抜けた日々
The days we ran through
語り合ったグローリー
The glory we talked about together
今 答えたい 生きてると 背中押す声 熱くなる
I want to answer now that I'm alive, the voices pushing my back become hot
夢は夢のまま 終われない！
A dream cannot end as just a dream!
君と 未来描きゴール目指し
With you, drawing the future toward the goal
狙い定め掴めウィニング
Take aim and seize the winning
ずっとずっとずっとずっと想い 夢はきっと叶うから
Because the feelings and dreams I've always held will surely come true
あの日君が鳴らした 涙も信じて
Believing even in the tears you shed that day
雨も風も雲も闇も声 描き焦がれ走れ
Rain, wind, clouds, and darkness, voices run toward the yearning we drew
あぁ 勝利へ！
Ah, toward victory!
揺るぎない覚悟決して
With unwavering determination
一つ二つ共に綴る記録
One, two, records we write together
背中に迫る迷い振り払え 今の自分追い越すだけ
Shake off the hesitation closing in behind, just overtake your current self
勝ちたい！ 勝ちたい！ 勝ちたい！ 君と勝ちたい！
I want to win! I want to win! I want to win! I want to win with you!
はーい！
Here we go!
未来描きゴール目指し
Drawing the future toward the goal
狙い定め掴めウィニング
Take aim and seize the winning
ずっとずっとずっとずっと想い 夢はきっと叶うから
Because the feelings and dreams I've always held will surely come true
あの日君が鳴らした 涙も信じて
Believing even in the tears you shed that day
春も夏も秋も冬も声 雨も風も超え
Spring, summer, autumn, and winter voices, over the rain and wind
雲も闇も超え 勝利へ
Over the clouds and darkness, to victory
君と
With you
走り競いゴール目指し
Running and competing toward the goal
遥か響け届けミュージック
Resonate and reach far, music
ずっとずっとずっとずっと想い 夢がきっと叶うなら
If the feelings and dreams I've always held surely come true
あの日君に感じた 何かを信じて
Believing in something I felt from you that day
夏も秋も冬も越え
Beyond the summers, the autumns, and the winters
願い焦がれ走れ
Run with longing for your wishes
あぁ 勝利へ
Ah, towards victory!
No stop, no stop to finish!
STARTING OVER
作詞：さめざめおり　作曲・編曲：柳田圭介
Lyrics: Samezameori / Composition & Arrangement: Yanagida Keisuke
It's finally the true end
I'm ready for... my destiny
I'm ready for... STARTING OVER
やっと幕を下ろせた 最後の瞬間まで
Finally, I was able to lower the curtain, until the very last moment
わたしは精一杯に わたしをやりきった
I gave it my all, and played my part to the very end
終演の続きは 誰も知らなくていい
No one needs to know what follows the end of the show
涙を置いて 新しい旅に出よう
Let's leave our tears behind and set out on a new journey
熱狂はあなたを選ぶ 違う結末だっただけ
The excitement chooses you; it was just a different outcome
同じ愛になれなかった Destiny
A destiny that couldn't become the same love
これまでの全てを 差し出すような愛だった
It was a love where I offered up everything I had
世界の意味が変わるくらいに 肯定された気がしたんだ
I felt so affirmed that it felt like the meaning of the world had changed
何気なさの中で 気づけた最初の奇跡が
The first miracle I noticed in the midst of the mundane...
あなたでよかった わたしでよかった 心から思えたよ
...was that I'm glad it was you, and I'm glad it was me. I truly felt that from my heart
ずっと遠い未来も ちゃんと覚えていよう
Let's remember this well, even in the far-off future
自分の抱きしめかた 明日の願いかた
How to embrace myself, how to wish for tomorrow
あなたがいなくても わたしの片隅で
Even if you're not there, in a corner of my heart...
優しい光 消えたりしないとわかる
...I know a gentle light will never fade
今はまだ手を振れるほど 道は別れたばかりで
For now, I can only wave goodbye, as our paths have only just split
後ろ髪に風を感じながら
While feeling the wind pulling at the back of my hair
それまでの全てが あなたに出会うためだった
Everything up until then was for the sake of meeting you
どの瞬間もムダじゃないこと 本当の意味で知れたから
Because I've learned in the truest sense that no moment was wasted
次の曲がり角も 自分らしさで選べるはず
I should be able to choose the next turn in my own way
いつかに繋がる 新しい一歩 信じて歩き出そう
Let's start walking, believing in the new step that leads to a "someday"
心から誰かを愛せた あの日々は
Those days when I could love someone from the bottom of my heart...
間違いなくわたしの Destiny Ah
...were undoubtedly my destiny, ah
これまでの全てが 新しい力をくれる
Everything up until now gives me new strength
どの瞬間もムダじゃないなら 何が起きても大丈夫だから
If no moment is wasted, then I'll be fine no matter what happens
次の物語も 自分らしさで選べるはず
I should be able to choose the next story in my own way
いつかに繋がる わたしのはじまり 信じて歩き出そう
Let's start walking, believing in my beginning that leads to a "someday"
いつか繋がる　わたしのはじまり　信じて歩き出そう
Someday we'll connect; it's my beginning; let's walk forth with belief
再び幕は上がる
The curtain rises once again
聞いていただいたのは新曲の『STARTING OVER』でした！
The song you just heard was my new song, "STARTING OVER"!
はい、新年一発目、新曲の初披露というわけで、ぬるっとね、新曲をやってしまったんですが…
Yes, the first new song performance of the year—I just casually went ahead and performed it...
平成感のある、懐かしみの感じの楽曲をこちらですね、歌わせていただいたんですけども…
I sang this song, which has a bit of a nostalgic Heisei-era feel to it...
このあと、この曲が、24時から、あともう数時間か、24時からですね…
And following this, at midnight—just a few hours from now—at midnight...
1月30日の24時から、配信、リリースされます。たくさん聴いてください！
Starting from midnight on January 30th, the song will be released for streaming. Please listen to it a lot!
今年もね、たくさんオリ曲出していきたいです！
I want to keep releasing lots of original songs this year too!
そしてそして、もうMCがね、実は最後なのでね、えーっと、この配信のあとにはメンバー限定の配信もあるのでよろしくお願いします！
And also, this is actually the final MC segment, so there will be a member-only stream after this. Don't miss it!
よしよしよし、グッズ紹介！
Alright, alright, alright, time for the goods introduction!
えーここには、同期のねぽらぼを大集合っていうことで、えーっと、ね、ら、ぼ、集まれー！
And here, I'm bringing together my gen-mates, NePoLaBo! Ne, Ra, Bo, assemble!
イエーイ！
Yay!
ちゃちゃちゃちゃ、初めて呼びました。どうも。
Cha-cha-cha-cha, first time I've called you guys here. Hello.
あれ初だっけ？
Wait, is this the first time?
ポルカチャンネル初！
First time on Polka's channel!
お誕生日おめでとう！おめでとう！
Happy birthday! Congratulations!
ここまでが流れでございます。はい。ずっと待ってたから。
That's the planned flow. Yes. I've been waiting for this.
グッズをね、紹介させていただきたいと思います。みなさんに失礼ながらのリアクションなど各々取っていただけると嬉しいです。
I'd like to introduce the goods now. I'd appreciate it if you all could give your own reactions, if you don't mind.
ガヤガヤガヤ！
Chatter chatter!
というわけで、尾丸ポルカ誕生日記念グッズ2026、ラインナップはこちら！ドン！ドン！
So, here's the lineup for Omaru Polka Birthday Celebration Goods 2026! Ta-da!
ドン！ドン！
Ta-da!
尾丸ポルカ 誕生日記念 2026 / 記念グッズ4種 / 特典ASMRボイス / 直筆メッセージ入りチェキ風ブロマイドカード
Omaru Polka Birthday Celebration 2026 / 4 types of commemorative goods / Bonus ASMR voice / Cheki-style bromide card with handwritten message
というわけで、素晴らしい、今回もラインナップが揃っております！
And so, we have another wonderful lineup this time!
なんか… あれ？ ちょっと… あれれ？
Something's... Wait? A bit... Huh?
盛ってませんよ！盛ってませんね！というわけで、まず一つ一つ解していきましょう。
I'm not padding! No padding here! Anyway, let's break them down one by one.
まずはこちら、はい。ポルカのはじめての抱き枕カバーになっております！
First up is this. Yes. It's Polka's first-ever hugging pillow cover!
ポルカのはじめて抱き枕カバー / イラスト：パセリ
Polka's First Hugging Pillow Cover / Illustration: Parsley
すごーい！ ちょっとパンツ履いてませんか？
Wow! Wait, aren't you wearing panties?
え、丸出しじゃないですか？
Wait, isn't it completely exposed?
部屋着だよ！
It's room wear!
だっておねねだってこういう部屋着だもん。
But even Nene has room wear like this.
ひとおのチャンネルだからってやりたい放題チャンネルして！
Doing whatever you want just because it's someone else's channel!
シャツで寝たらシワつくぞ！
If you sleep in a shirt, it'll get wrinkled!
写真撮影用かもしれないです！
It might be for the photoshoot!
というわけで、はじめて抱き枕カバー出します。表が通常衣装で、裏は彼シャツになってます！
So, I'm releasing my first hugging pillow cover. The front is my regular outfit, and the back is "boyfriend shirt" style!
彼シャツ！
Boyfriend shirt!
パセリ先生ありがとう！
Thank you, Parsley-sensei!
続きまして、ドン！ こちら、歴代衣装のポルカランダムラバーストラップです！
Next, ta-da! Here are the Omaru Polka Random Rubber Straps featuring my past outfits!
歴代衣装のポルカ ランダムラバーストラップ / イラスト：のいみね
Past Outfit Polka Random Rubber Strap / Illustration: Noimine
かわいい！
Cute!
これまでの衣装のラバーストラップ、こちら、のいみね先生に書いていただきました！
These past outfit rubber straps were illustrated by Noimine-sensei!
続きまして、こちら、ドン！ どれもこれも宝物思い出バインダー！
Moving on, this, ta-da! The "Everything is a Treasure Memory Binder"!
どれもこれも宝物思い出バインダー
Everything is a Treasure Memory Binder
最近みんな特典でチェキ風のブロマイドカード出したりしてるから、そういうの入れられたり…
Since everyone's been giving out cheki-style bromide cards as bonuses lately, you can put those in here...
あとはホロカも入るサイズになってますので、ぜひぜひいろんな思い出しまってください！
And it's also sized for Hololive Cards, so please store all kinds of memories in it!
続きましては、こちら！ ポルカのしっぽキーホルダー！
Next up is this! Polka's Tail Keychain!
ポルカのしっぽキーホルダー
Polka's Tail Keychain
一周して流行ってるからね。ポルカのしっぽ型のキーホルダー。
They've come back into style. A Polka tail-shaped keychain.
平成レトロみたいな感じで出ております。こちらも付けてください！
It's got a bit of a Heisei retro vibe. Please wear this one too!
そしてボイスも出ます。ボイスはこちら！ じゃーん！ ASMRボイスです！
And there's a voice pack too. Here it is! Ta-da! It's an ASMR voice!
ASMRボイス / 「彼シャツポルカの、ただいまの抱擁。」
ASMR Voice / "Boyfriend Shirt Polka's 'Welcome Home' Hug."
『彼シャツポルカの、ただいまの抱擁』というちょっとタイトルもなんか狙ってる感満載で…
It's titled "Boyfriend Shirt Polka's 'Welcome Home' Hug," which definitely feels like it's aiming for something...
エッ〇！ てんこ盛り！
Sexy! Full service!
なんで今日同期呼んじゃったんだろうって一瞬思った、今。恥ずかしくなってきた。
I just wondered for a second why I invited my gen-mates today. I'm starting to feel embarrassed.
添い寝ASMRというか、抱き枕カバーとイラストの関係がある仕様になってます！
It's co-sleeping ASMR, and it's designed to complement the hugging pillow cover illustration!
はい皆様お待たせしました。フルセット購入特典、こちら！
Alright, thanks for waiting. Here's the full set purchase bonus!
チェキ風ブロマイドカード！ 数量限定が直筆メッセージ、箔押し複製サインになっております！
A cheki-style bromide card! The limited quantity version features a handwritten message and a foil-stamped replica signature!
フルセット購入特典 / チェキ風ブロマイドカード / 特典ASMRボイス / 「すやすやポルカの、いちばん近い約束。」
Full Set Purchase Bonus / Cheki-style bromide card / Bonus ASMR voice / "Snoozing Polka's Closest Promise."
通常が箔押し複製サインとメッセージ入りでございます。
The standard version includes a foil-stamped replica signature and message.
フルセット買っていただいた方には、特典ボイスとして『すやすやポルカの、いちばん近い約束』という添い寝ボイスも…
For those who buy the full set, the bonus voice is "Snoozing Polka's Closest Promise," a co-sleeping voice...
「一緒に寝ようね」みたいな感じの
It's like, "Let's sleep together."
なんかちょっとそういったボイスになってて
The voice is kind of like that.
こっちもASMRになってます
This one is also in ASMR.
よろしくお願いします
Thank you for your support.
恥ずかしいな、みんなとやるのこれ
This is embarrassing, doing this with everyone.
なんかエッチな女になってしまって...
I've become some kind of lewd woman...
すいません すいません
Sorry, sorry.
いいじゃない！
It's fine!
新年もね、皆さん改めてこれからよろしくお願いします
As for the new year, I look forward to your continued support.
というわけでね、今日はみんなで最後、一緒に歌うために呼んできたということで
So, I've called everyone here today to sing together for the finale.
準備してきました！
I've come prepared!
行ってみましょう！ジャン！
Let's go! Ta-da!
ポルカ、フィナーレ！
POLKATIC FINALE!
脚本は捨てちゃおうか
Shall we throw away the script?
差し当たり焼き付けよう
For now, let's burn it in.
アドリブの熱いパフォーマンス
A passionate ad-lib performance.
屋根裏を飛び出して
Flying out of the attic,
壮大なステージに響く
Resonating on a grand stage,
特別なストーリー
A special story.
瞼の裏には
Behind my eyelids,
虹が輝く
A rainbow shines.
星空のメモリー
Memories of the starry sky.
等身大の愛を込めて
With a true-to-life love,
想像を超える世界へ
To a world beyond imagination.
誰も知らないでしょう
Nobody knows it yet, right?
Are You Ready?
どんな未来が見に行こうよ
Let's go see what kind of future awaits.
なんて自由だ笑っちゃうよね
It's so free, it makes me laugh.
ねぇ ホログラムよりも先へ
Hey, further than even a hologram.
誰だって置いてかないよ
I won't leave anyone behind.
ごらん歓声が呼んでいる
Look, the cheers are calling.
ステップからパッと照らす
Instantly illuminating from the steps,
人生のスポットライト
The spotlight of life.
薔薇色のプレミアイショー
A rose-colored premier show.
ここが特等席よ
This is the best seat in the house.
お披露目はお遊びより
The debut is more than just play,
天気次第のエチュード
An etude depending on the weather.
まるで物語
Just like a story.
捕まえてよ
Catch me.
待って
Wait.
ほら待って
Hey, wait.
予想のできない展開に
In an unpredictable development,
ステージは揺れる
The stage shakes.
格別のストーリー
An exceptional story.
耳を澄ましたら
If you listen closely,
月が踊る
The moon dances.
雨粒のハーモニー
Harmony of raindrops.
浮かぶふわふわな空想
Fluffy fantasies float by.
暴走底なしの本能
Out-of-control, bottomless instinct.
すべて知りたいでしょう
You want to know everything, don't you?
Hey Guys! 叫べ気分は最高！ (最高！)
Hey Guys! Shout it out, the feeling's the best! (The best!)
Come on! もっと叫べ気分は最高！ (最高！)
Come on! Shout it out more, the feeling's the best! (The best!)
ポルカ終わるか？
Will Polka end?
終わらない
It won't end.
It's showtime!
繋いだ手離さないでなんてね
Don't let go of my hand, I say.
どうしたって重たくなっちゃって困るわ
No matter what, it gets too heavy and it's troublesome.
いつの日かエピローグを一緒に綴ろう
Someday, let's write the epilogue together.
きっと約束よ
It's a promise.
Life goes on!
どんな未来が見に行こうよ
Let's go see what kind of future awaits.
なんて自由だ笑っちゃうよね
It's so free, it makes me laugh.
ねぇ ホログラムよりも先へ
Hey, further than even a hologram.
夢のような花舞台に感情を馳せたら
When feelings are poured onto a dream-like stage,
ステップからパッと照らす
Instantly illuminating from the steps,
人生のスポットライト
The spotlight of life.
薔薇色のプレミアイショー
A rose-colored premier show.
どこへだって添い遂げたい
I want to stay together wherever we go.
ここが特等席よ
This is the best seat in the house.
Yeah!
Let's go!
あんたにゃ　もったいない
It's too good for you
あたいは本当　ナイスバディ　バディ　バディ
I really have a nice body, body, body
自分で言うくらい
So much that I'd say it myself
ただじゃ　ない　ない　ない　アハハン
I'm not just ordinary, no, no, no, ah-ha-han
あっけにゃ　冷めちまう
It'll cool down in a flash
寂しけりゃ　Everybody　Body　Body
If you're lonely, Everybody Body Body
誰にも　分かんない
Nobody knows
恋愛って　いつ火がつくのか
When will the fire of love catch?
ダイナマイト
Dynamite
恋はダイナマイト
Love is dynamite
どんなに　不景気だって　恋はインフレーション
No matter how bad the economy is, love is inflation
こんなに　優しくされちゃ　みだら
Being treated so kindly makes me feel wanton
明るい　未来に
In a bright future
就職希望だわ　Wow Wow Wow Wow
I want to get a job, Wow Wow Wow Wow
日本の未来は
Japan's future is
世界がうらやむ　Yeah Yeah Yeah Yeah
The envy of the world, Yeah Yeah Yeah Yeah
恋をしようじゃないか
Let's fall in love, shall we?
Dance! Dancin' all of the night
なんだか　物足りない
Something's not quite enough
どこにいたって　愛しててほしいわ
Wherever you are, I want you to love me
自分で　伝えるの
I'll tell you myself
恥ずかしく　ない　ない　ない
It's not embarrassing, no, no, no
いっそのこと　二人で
How about just the two of us?
憧れよ　Everybody　Body　Body
Admire us, Everybody Body Body
誰もが　気づいてない
Nobody has realized
恋愛って　夢の落とし穴
Love is a dream's trap
ミステリー
Mystery
恋はミステリー
Love is a mystery
そんなの　不自然だって　恋のインサイダー
Even if that's unnatural, love's insider
それでも　情熱にされちゃ　あらわ
Even so, if passion is shown, it's exposed
幸せ　来る日も
Even on happy days
キャンセル待ちなの　Wow Wow Wow Wow
I'm on a waiting list, Wow Wow Wow Wow
あんたの笑顔は
Your smile is
世界がうらやむ　Yeah Yeah Yeah Yeah
The envy of the world, Yeah Yeah Yeah Yeah
夢があるじゃないか
There's a dream, isn't there?
Dance! Dancin' all of the night
Wake up!
LOVE LOVE LOVE マシーン　Wow Wow Wow Wow
LOVE LOVE LOVE Machine Wow Wow Wow Wow
LOVE LOVE LOVE ステーション　Yeah Yeah Yeah Yeah
LOVE LOVE LOVE Station Yeah Yeah Yeah Yeah
LOVE LOVE LOVE ファクトリー　Wow Wow Wow Wow
LOVE LOVE LOVE Factory Wow Wow Wow Wow
LOVE　LOVE IS SO WONDERFUL
LOVE LOVE IS SO WONDERFUL
イェーイ！
Yay!
日本の未来は
Japan's future is
世界がうらやむ　Yeah Yeah Yeah Yeah
The envy of the world, Yeah Yeah Yeah Yeah
恋をしようじゃないか
Let's fall in love, shall we?
Dance! Dancin' all of the night
老いも若きも
Old and young
あんたもあたしも　Yeah Yeah Yeah Yeah
You and I, Yeah Yeah Yeah Yeah
みんなも社長さんも
Everyone, even the president
Dance! Dancin' all of the night
LOVEマシーン
Love Machine
今日は主役だ！！ まだまだ かがやく場所へ つれていくぜ！！ I LOVE YOU ♡ 2026.1.30
Today I'm the star!! I'll take you to even brighter places!! I LOVE YOU ♡ 2026.1.30
ポルカのライブ過去最多 ホロメンゲスト 10名 新曲のお披露目あり！ Glitter Love 1/30 21:00～
Polka's live with the most guests ever: 10 Hololive members. New song reveal! Glitter Love. 1/30 21:00~
#尾丸ポルカ生誕祭2026
新曲のお披露目あり！
Glitter Love
ポルカのライブ過去最多 ホロメンゲスト10名
#OmaruPolkaBirthday2026
New song reveal!
Glitter Love
Polka's live with the most guests ever: 10 Hololive members